<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chef, | SiR by John Morales]]></title>
  <link href="http://JohnMorales.github.io/blog/categories/chef/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://JohnMorales.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-04T18:14:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://JohnMorales.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Morales]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[reviewing the opsworks cookbooks]]></title>
    <link href="http://JohnMorales.github.io/blog/2014/04/20/reviewing-the-opsworks-cookbooks/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T16:26:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://JohnMorales.github.io/blog/2014/04/20/reviewing-the-opsworks-cookbooks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The most important thing when using OpsWorks if you come from a Chef Server
background is that its a fundamental shift in configuration management. The
traditional chef model is that the nodes always converge to the state defined
by the runlist. The client should poll for changes to the runlist or the recipe
list that is expanded to by the runlist. In the opsworks model, the clients are
not expected to poll for changes. Instead they are notified to converge to
specific states based on a few key events. So fundamentally the model is a push
instead of a pull.</p>

<p>In these events there are a few opsworks recipes that are run. There is no way
to not run them. After the OpsWorks cookbooks run then you have the opportunity
to provide your own custom cookbooks. In addition you can use a feature of Chef
that I was not aware of. You can override a AWS provided template or attribute in
your cookbook. <em>Note that you cannot override a recipe.</em></p>

<p>After reviewing the AWS OpsWorks documentation I head over to the opensource cookbooks:
The first thing I notice is that the documentation in the source code is sparse. I start with the Rakefile</p>

<h2>Rakefile</h2>

<p>The rakefile contains a suite of custom line based validators for coding standards.</p>

<p>task validate_literal_include:
  goes through all the ruby files and makes sure that it can find any recipes that are included.
task validate_attribute_dependencies
  goes through each attribute and checks for attribute references and include attribute references, makes sure that they true up. Seems useful.
task validate_syntax
  runs ruby -c on every ruby file.. also useful
task validate_best_pactrise
  runs foodcritic linter on the whole project
task validate_customize
  Every cookbook should include an customize.rb attribute?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My thoughts of ChefConf 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://JohnMorales.github.io/blog/2014/04/18/my-thoughts-of-chefconf-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-18T10:20:18-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://JohnMorales.github.io/blog/2014/04/18/my-thoughts-of-chefconf-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m sitting at the SFO airport trying to digest everything that I was exposed
to after 3 intense days of Chef sessions and meeting the awesome chef
community.</p>

<h2>Community</h2>

<p>One thing that I learned is that Chef as a company is cool and laid back. I was
taken by surprise on how cool they are. After watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0P0HD5pE-zU">Nathen Harvey&rsquo;s
presentation</a> and then the open
bar rock band show I realized how down to earth and funny they are. Even
everyone that I met at all the hallway sessions were friends I hadn&rsquo;t met yet.
I felt wow these guys are genuinely awesome. I was initially skeptical because
I thought that everyone was a little too nice and friendly, but by the end I
was convinced that this is an awesome community, that I&rsquo;m glad to be a part of.</p>

<h2>Message</h2>

<p>The message that I recieved from the conference was that we as IT professionals
have the power to change companies. We need to fully embrace the idea of
continous delivery (which admittely I need to learn more about). That the
devops movement is a shift in how software is maintained and that the shift
requires more transparency, acceptance and trust than just adding a new
&lsquo;configuration management&rsquo; tool.  I learned that it&rsquo;s about building trust in
the process. Showing real success stories in baby steps so that everyone can
realize the potential that we sell them in slide decks and proposals.</p>

<p>Lastly the idea that we are all working together to make
the software development process more delightful. By implementing a process
that reduces the friction in changes we&rsquo;re able to respond faster and provide
value.</p>

<h2>Call to action</h2>

<ul>
<li>Be a prophet of the devops movement.</li>
<li>Make sure I lead a healthy life, since unhealthy lives suck.</li>
<li>Read

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Continuous-Delivery-Deployment-Automation-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321601912"><em>Continous Delivery</em></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Project-DevOps-Helping-Business-ebook/dp/B00AZRBLHO/"><em>The Phoenix Project</em></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Once-Future-King-T-H-White-ebook/dp/B00AEDDSQG"><em>The once and future king</em></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Hard-Thing-About-Things-Building-ebook/dp/B00DQ845EA/"><em>The hard thing about hard things</em></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practical-Approach-Large-Scale-Agile-Development/dp/0321821726"><em>A pratical approach to Large Scale Agile Development</em></a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
